Seward, Ralph Additional Papers 5970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Ralph Seward Additional Papers
1942-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seward, Ralph
5970
12 cubic feet
12 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Consists of National Academy of Arbitrators (NAA) records and arbitration decisions regarding United Steelworkers of America (USWA), United Auto Workers (UAW), Communication Workers of America (CWA), Airlines, and Telephone Companies.
3126436
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, May 27, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Arbitrator and mediator; member, National Mediation Service, National Defense Mediation Board; impartial umpire for cases involving the dairy, auto and steel industries, among others.
Ralph Seward (BA., Cornell University, 1927; MA., New York University, 1931; LLB., Columbia University, 1935) served as an attorney with the National Labor Relations Board (1936-1937) and was executive secretary (1937-1939) and general counsel (1939) of the New York State Labor Relations Board. He also served as chairman of the Board of Immigration Appeals, U.S. Department of Justice (1939-1941), as executive secretary, National Defense Mediation Board (1941-1942), and as associate public member of the U.S. National War Labor Board (1942) before going into private practice as an arbitrator and mediator. In addition to chairing two Emergency Boards of the National Mediation Service, Seward was impartial chairman for the metropolitan New York milk industry (1942-1944); impartial umpire for General Motors Corporation and the United Automobile Workers (1944-1947); chairman of the Board of Conciliation and Arbitration of United States Steel Corporation and United Steelworkers of America (1947-1949); impartial umpire for International Harvester Company and United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers of America (1949-1951); impartial umpire for Bethlehem Steel Corporation and the United Steelworkers of America (1952); and arbitrator and/or mediator in various other cases.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5328: Ralph T. Seward Papers 5069: U.S. Wage Stabilization Board 1952 United Steelworkers of America Case 5113: Ralph T. Seward Arbitration Transcripts and Exhibits 5700: Ralph T. Seward Additional Arbitration Files 5779: Ralph T. Seward Additional Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Seward, Ralph T. (Ralph Theodore), 1907-
3126436
- NAA files; Arbitration files; speeches. (Box 1)
  - News Clipping: RTS, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Arbitrators, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - N.A.A. American Bar Association Committee Report on the Training of New Arbitrators for Academy Action, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - N.A.A. - Continuing Cooperation with Appointing Agencies Bill Simkin's Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Continuing Cooperation with Appointing Agencies, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - N.A.A. - Special Committee on Continuing Cooperation with Appointed Agencies - Meeting of Central Group and AAA - New York City - January 16, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Special Committee on Grievance Machinery, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - N.A.A. Newsletters, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Development and Long Range Goals, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - N.A.A. - Dues Waiver Policy Committee - and Related Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - National Academy of Arbitrators - Ethics Committee, 1955-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - N.A.A. Committee - Ethics Opinion No. 3 "Case of the Loquacious Letterhead", 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Conference April 12-13, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - National Labor Relations Board - Statement by Herzog before Senate Committee, 4-28-53, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Mediation Board, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Misc., 1969-1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Metal Trades Dept. AFL-CIO (Impartial Referees Panel) RTS on list., 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arbitration Board #282 (RR) Award of Arbitration March 4, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Emergency Board #176, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ILR School - Cornell, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Arbitration Bd. No. 282 Speech Before Committee on Commerce, U.S. Senate, August 31, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Arbitration Bd. No. 282 Speech before Committee on Commerce U.S. Senate, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Speech: November 26, 1962 How Effective are Third Parties (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Speech - February 4, 1960 "Arbitration and the Functions of Management" - Cornell (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Speech - October 23, 1960 "Arbitration of Incentive Grievances" N.Y. State School of Industrial and Labor Relations - Ithaca, N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Speech - October 23, 1959 "Arbitration of Incentive Grievances" N.Y. State School of Industrial and Labor Relations - Ithaca N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Speech - August 2, 1958 "The Emerging 'Industrial Jurisprudence'" - University of Michigan Law School (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Speeches - University of Penna. Wharton School of Finance - 4-21-1964 - Labor Relations Council (Box 1, Folder 29)
- NAA Files (includes Committee files, etc.). (Box 2)
  - N.A.A. - Special Committee on Continuing Cooperation with the Appointing Agencies - 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - N.A.A. - Speeches (of Members of N.A.A.), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - N.A.A.: Self-Employed Individuals Retirement Tax Act of '62, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - N.A.A.: Retirement Plan, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - N.A.A. - Officers, Governors, and Committee Chairmen, List of From 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - N.A.A. Past President's Committee Princeton Inn, December 6-7, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - N.A.A. - Committee on Prof. Responsibility and Grievances, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Program, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - N.A.A. Arbitrators - Aaron Horvitz, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - N.A.A. Arbitrators - Peter Seitz, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - N.A.A. Arbitrators - Gabe Alexander, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - N.A.A. Arbitrators Charles O. Gregory, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - N.A.A. Arbitrators - W. Willard Wirtz, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Arbitrator Industry Comments on Various Drafts of the Code, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - N.A.A., 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - N.A.A. Meetings Annual - April-May, 1953 (Detroit) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - N.A.A. Meetings - Annual - Chicago, Illinois, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - N.A.A. Meetings, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - N.A.A. Meeting - Annual - Washington, D.C., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - N.A.A. Meetings - Annual - Washington, D.C., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - N.A.A. Annual Meetings - Guest Lists, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - NAA - Professional Responsibility, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - N.A.A. Etc., 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - N.A.A., 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - N.A.A. Special Committee on Professionalism, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Drafts, Worksheets, Sunkin Memos, RTS Notes, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - N.A.A. - Jan. 31, 1964- New York Annual Mtg: RTS Speech: Speech Work Assignments and Industrial Change: The Rights of Management, Unions (Box 2, Folder 27)
- NAA Files (includes Committee files, etc.). (Box 3)
  - Ethics Committee - Working Drafts and Related Papers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speech: National Academy of Arbitrators, April 8, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - N.A.A. Annual Meeting - April, 1972 RTS Speech Material (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - N.A.A. - Re-examination Committee, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - N.A.A. Meeting - Regional, 1977-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Research and Education, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - N.A.A. - Special Survey Committee - Committees RTS, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - N.A.A. - Membership Classification Committee - R.T.S. - Chairman, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - N.A.A. - Liaison Committee R.T.S., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - N.A.A. - Guest Policy - Special Committee, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Disputes Settlement in Public Employment, Special Committee, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - N.A.A. - Committee on Training of New Arbitrators, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Structural (Special Committee - 1960) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Seward File Research and Education Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Seward File Ethics Committee, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - N.A.A. - Ethics, Code of (1967) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Ethics, 1959-1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ethics Committee Meeting - Bar Harbor, Maine, 8/8-12/1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - N.A.A. - Special Committee on Continuing Cooperation with Appointing Agencies - Meeting of Central Group- Oct. 16, 1959 Washington, D.C. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Legislation Committee, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Seward File Nominating Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ethics Committee - General Correspondence and Memorandums, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - N.A.A. Committees - Law and Legislation, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Steel Arbitration; Conferences; Speeches; Misc.. (Box 4)
  - Conference on Adjustment to Automation Univ. of Penna. - May 21, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Univ. of Virginia School of Law Seminar - May 11, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - President's Conference on Industrial Safety - Proceedings of Annual Meeting, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ralph T. Seward - Speeches, 1938-1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Continuing Legal Education, U. of Mich. Ann Arbor Labor-Arbitration Conf. 7-12, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: American Iron and Steel Institute- New York City January 6, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ad Hoc Arbitrators - Peter Seitz, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Simkin, William, N.A.A. Arbitrator, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bethlehem and U.S.A. Arbitration Procedure (Incentive Grievances), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Seminar - Lackawanna Staff Reps. July 15, 1976: R.T.S. - Conducting (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bethlehem Steel Corporation - vs. U.S.A.,: Discrimination Case Finding of Fact and Conclusions of Law. U.S. District Court, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - United Steelworkers of America - Grievance Procedure Questioned, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bethlehem- U.S.A. - Steel Strike 1959 - Injunction signed by Judge H.P. Sora October 21, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration of 1974 Steel Contract - RTS (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Bethlehem Steel Co. - Incentive Material Development and Application of Present Bethlehem Incentive Policy, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bethlehem and U.S.A. - Agreement -January 4, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Steel Arbitration - General Contract Negotiations - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Arbitration Case Files. (Box 5)
  - Report of the Presidential Board, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Journal Co. + The Milwaukee Sentinel Division of the Hearst Corporation, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Washington Newspaper Guild -and- The Washington Post Co., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bethlehem Steel Co. -and- Draftsman Guild, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - I.A.M. -and- United Air Lines Gr. 23812-SFO (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - VEPCO -and- IBEW July 13, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - New York Telephone Co. + CWA, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New England Telephone + IBEW, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - International Harvester Company -and- International Union, Auto., Aircraft, Agric. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Seward, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - So. Bell + Comm. Workers of America, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - United States Postal Service -and- Amer. Postal Workers Union, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Western Airlines + International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - GP of MD -and- Communication Workers of America (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - So. Central Bell Tele. Co. + Communications Workers of Amer. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - American Airlines -and- Airline Stewards + Stewardesses Assoc., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - National Airlines Inc. -and- Airline Dispatchers Association, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - IAM + Aerospace Workers -and- United Assoc. of Journeymen + Apprentices, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Milk Industry + Mgmt. Trustees August 12, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - American Airlines -and- Airline Stewardesses Assoc. 68-235+6, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - International Harvester Co. -and- IAM Jan. 13, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Titanium Metals Corp. of Amer. + United Steelworkers (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Wendell Jones vs. St. Louis Cardinals, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - United States Postal Service Assoc. of Letter Carriers (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hotel Industry Dispute 1976 (Bd. Of Inquiry) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - IAM + IAW -and- IBEW April 2, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - L+P Telephone -and- Communications (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Briggs + Co. -and- Amalgamated Meat Cutters + Butcher Workmen, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Kansas City Star Company + Kansas City Web Printing Pressman's, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Gould Inc. 9-15-76 "No Strike" Clause, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Memphis Publishing Co + (Wages + Hosp. Fund), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Memphis Publishing Co. + Memphis Newspaper Printing, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Coordinating Committee Steel Co's. + United Steelworkers of America, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - International Union of Gas Workers + Washington Gas Light Co., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Bermuda - 2nd Hearing, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Washington Gas Light Co. + OFC + Professional Employees, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Titanium Metals Corp. + United Steelworkers of America (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Titanium Metals Corp. + United Steelworkers of America, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - International Printing + Graphic Union + The Wash Publishers Assoc., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - So. Central Bell Telephone Co. -and- CWA, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - New York Telephone Co. + CBA, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Western Electric Co. + IBEW, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - So. Central Bell Telephone + CWA Gr. 75-96-307 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - IBEW -and- New England Telephone Co., 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Seward, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - New Jersey Bell and IBEW L.827 June 9 and 10, 1987 - Discharge: Albright (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - So. Central Bell Telephone Co. -and- CWA (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - So. Bell Telephone + Telegraph Co. + CWA, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Sunshine Products Industries + International United Employees, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Bermuda Case March 13, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- International Harvester Co. Decisions. (Box 6)
  - Permanent Arbitrator, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Bound
  - International Harvester Company vs. United Farm Equipment Workers of America, Local No. 104, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - International Harvester Company, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - International Harvester Company - Melrose Park Works, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- International Harvester Co. Decisions. (Box 7)
  - International Harvester Company - United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers Council-UE, Local 107, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - International Harvester Company McCormick Works -, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - International Harvester Company Canton Works, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - International Harvester Company East Moline Works, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- International Harvester (cont); Presidents National Labor-Management Conference, 1945 (6 vols. ); Kaiser Co. Industrial Relations Conference F'roceedings, 1956. (Box 8)
  - The President's National Labor-Management Conference - Volume 1, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The President's National Labor-Management Conference Volume 2 Plenary Sessions, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The President's National Labor-Management Conference Volume 3 Reports of working Committees, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The President's National Labor-Management Conference Volume 4 Public Hearings Committee Reports, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The President's National Labor-Management Conference Volume 5 - Press Conference, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The President's National Labor-Management Conference Volume 4 - Miscellaneous Documents, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings of the Kaiser Companies Industrial, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - United Steelworkers of America, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Ad Hoc Decisions (bd. vols.) Alpha order by company. (Box 9)
  - Ad Hoc Decisions "B" Volume, 1957-1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "L" to "R" Volume 3, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ad Hoc Decision "S" to "Z" Volume 4Selas Corporation of America, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ad Hoc Decision "A" Volume 1, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Alco Products, Inc. -and- United Steelworkers of America, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- International Assn. of Machinists Dia. Lodge 142; RR Arb. Bd. 282; Milk Industry Decisions; Steel Industry. (Box 10)
  - Report of the Joint Steel Industry-Union Contracting Out Review Commission, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ralph T. Seward, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - International Association of Machinists - District Lodge 142 System Board of Adjustment Decisions TWA, Inc., 1955-1960 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - International Association of Machinists District Lodge 142 Letters of Understanding TWA, Inc., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Decisions Handed Down by Ralph T. Seward in the Office of the Milk Industry Impartial Chairman: Between October 24, 1942 and September 8, 1944, 1942- 1944 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bethlehem Steel Company -and- United Steelworkers of America CIO, Local 2601, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Railroad Dispute Technology to Appointment of Arbitration Bd. 282, 1956-1963 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Swift and Co.; General Motors Umpire Decisions. (Box 11)
  - General Motors Decisions Rolf Valtin Umpire Also- UAW News Notes, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General Motors Corporation - U.A.W. - umpire Decisions C-1 thru E-115, 1945-1952 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Swift and Company - Seward, 1945-1952 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - General Motors Corporation -and- U.E.W. 8/25/50, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - General Motors Corporation -and- U.A.W., 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - General Motors Corporation -and- U.A.W. Umpire Decisions 8/24/48 - 1963, 1948-1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- General Motors (cont). (Box 12)
  - General Motors Corporation -and- U.A.W., 1950 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - International Harvester Company - United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers of America, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Awards of Herbert C. Blumer, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Awards of Herbert C. Blumer, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Awards of Herbert C. Blumer, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)